Justice at any cost.
Law Abiding Citizen is a drama, crime, thriller film directed by F. Gary Gray.
A frustrated man decides to take justice into his own hands after a
plea bargain sets one of his family's killers free.
He targets not only the killer but also the district
attorney and others involved in the deal.
Nick Rice, played by Jamie Foxx.
Clyde Alexander Shelton, played by Gerard Butler.
Detective Dunnigan, played by Colm Meaney.
Jonas Cantrell, played by Bruce McGill.
Sarah Lowell, played by Leslie Bibb.
Detective Garza, played by Michael Irby.
Law Abiding Citizen is a 2009 American vigilante
action thriller film directed by F.
Gary Gray, written by Kurt Wimmer, and starring Jamie Foxx
and Gerard Butler (who also co-produced).
The film takes place in Philadelphia, telling the story of a man who seeks justice by targeting not only
his family's killer but also those who have supported a corrupt criminal justice system.
Law Abiding Citizen was filmed on location in Philadelphia and released
theatrically by Overture Films in North America on October 16, 2009.
The film grossed $127.9 million worldwide but received
generally negative reviews from critics.
Despite this, it was nominated for a Saturn Award as the Best Action/Adventure/Thriller Film of the year, as well as NAACP Image Award
nominations for both Foxx (Outstanding Actor in a Motion Picture) and Gray (Outstanding Directing in a Motion Picture).
The film explores themes of prison, assassin,
philadelphia, pennsylvania, bomb, secret passage.
The tone is emotional and intense.